[("SCE is an Associate Professor of Medicine at John's Hopkins Medical Center in Baltimore, MD.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (10, 30, 'PERSON'), (33, 41, 'DEPARTMENT'), (45, 74, 'ORG'), (78, 87, 'GPE')]}), ('Paresh Dandona, MD, PhD, SUNY Distinguished Professor, Chief of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, SUNY at Buffalo Founder and Director, Diabetes and Endocrinology Center of Western New York presented Novel Treatments of Type 1 Diabetes: Recent Advances at the Cleveland Clinic 24th Annual Diabetes Day.', {'entities': [(0, 14, 'PERSON'), (44, 53, 'PERSON'), (64, 77, 'DEPARTMENT'), (79, 87, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (92, 102, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (104, 119, 'ORG'), (120, 128, 'PERSON'), (132, 140, 'PERSON'), (142, 175, 'ORG'), (179, 195, 'GPE'), (212, 223, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (226, 241, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (266, 282, 'ORG'), (283, 307, 'EVENT')]}), ('HCP is a clinical pharmacist that specializes in cardiology at Allegheny General Hospital and Assistant Professor of Pharmacy Practice at Duquesne University in Pittsburgh, PA.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (9, 28, 'DESIGNATION'), (49, 59, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (63, 89, 'ORG'), (94, 113, 'PERSON'), (117, 134, 'DEPARTMENT'), (138, 157, 'ORG'), (161, 171, 'GPE')]}), ("The HCP is a Pulmonologist at Allegheny Health Network/ St. Vincent's in Erie, PA.", {'entities': [(4, 7, 'PERSON'), (13, 26, 'DESIGNATION'), (30, 69, 'ORG'), (73, 77, 'GPE')]}), ('SCE is a board certified in Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine and on staff at AMC Pulmonary & Critical Care Medicine in Albany, NY.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (28, 64, 'DEPARTMENT'), (72, 77, 'PERSON'), (81, 119, 'ORG'), (123, 129, 'GPE')]}), ('Dr. Gregory Lewis, President of the Amita Health Cardiology Group, would like to see further data on 30 day readmission rate for patients taking Jardiance.', {'entities': [(0, 17, 'PERSON'), (19, 28, 'DESIGNATION'), (36, 65, 'ORG'), (101, 103, 'CARDINAL'), (108, 119, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (129, 137, 'PERSON'), (145, 154, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Kim, Newburyport, Mass., is a D. O. in pulmonology at Anna Jacques Hospital with a clinical practice who is interested in becoming a speaker for BI.', {'entities': [(0, 6, 'PERSON'), (8, 19, 'GPE'), (33, 38, 'DESIGNATION'), (42, 53, 'DEPARTMENT'), (57, 79, 'ORG'), (86, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 143, 'PERSON')]}), ('Dr. Amy DeGueme, endocrinologist for Ascension Health System, speaker for Janssen for their SGLT2i presents at a Regional ADA conference in Wisconsin; audience is Certified Diabetic Educators.', {'entities': [(0, 15, 'PERSON'), (17, 32, 'DESIGNATION'), (37, 60, 'ORG'), (62, 69, 'PERSON'), (74, 81, 'ORG'), (86, 91, 'ORG'), (92, 98, 'ORG'), (112, 136, 'EVENT'), (140, 149, 'GPE'), (163, 191, 'PERSON')]}), ('Dr. Goran Rudic, MD is internist at Ascension Health System in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.', {'entities': [(0, 15, 'PERSON'), (23, 32, 'DESIGNATION'), (36, 59, 'ORG'), (63, 72, 'GPE'), (74, 83, 'GPE')]}), ('These experts, Jeff Kaliebe, Research Manager for the Aspirus Health Center, Wausau, WI, and David Murdock MD, General Cardiologist, stated reactive comments of the preclinical article "Empagliflozin ameliorates adverse left ventricular remodeling in non-diabetic pigs"They were excited to see the results of the LV Mass size decreased in the empa arm compared to control arm.', {'entities': [(6, 13, 'PERSON'), (15, 27, 'PERSON'), (29, 45, 'DESIGNATION'), (54, 75, 'ORG'), (77, 83, 'GPE'), (93, 106, 'PERSON'), (111, 131, 'DESIGNATION'), (165, 176, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (186, 211, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (225, 247, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (251, 263, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (269, 273, 'PERSON'), (313, 325, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (343, 351, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (364, 375, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Jaspal Singh, Medical Director of Pulmonary Innovation at Atrium Health located in Charlotte, NC states the barriers to a guideline directed patient care across the clinical continuum is largely due to malignment within the health system.', {'entities': [(0, 15, 'PERSON'), (17, 33, 'DESIGNATION'), (37, 57, 'DEPARTMENT'), (61, 74, 'ORG'), (86, 95, 'GPE'), (97, 99, 'GPE'), (144, 156, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (168, 186, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (227, 240, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('I was able to speak to 4 clinical pharmacists from Banner Health in Phoenix AZ.', {'entities': [(0, 1, 'PERSON'), (23, 24, 'CARDINAL'), (25, 45, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (51, 64, 'ORG'), (68, 78, 'GPE')]}), ('Steven Ginn, RN, BSN, BS Marketing, Barnes Hospital - Oncology UnitBJC Health System - St. Louis, MO New multidisciplinary oncology care team committee for improved performance of investigational drug studies Barnes Hospital is a leading teaching hospital based in St. Louis and is affiliated with Washington University School of Medicine and Siteman Cancer Center.', {'entities': [(0, 11, 'PERSON'), (36, 51, 'ORG'), (54, 67, 'DEPARTMENT'), (67, 84, 'ORG'), (85, 100, 'GPE'), (123, 141, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (196, 208, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (209, 224, 'ORG'), (247, 255, 'ORG'), (265, 274, 'GPE'), (298, 338, 'ORG'), (343, 364, 'ORG')]}), ('KDM is cardiologist Dr Ramos with Baycare.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 19, 'DESIGNATION'), (20, 28, 'PERSON'), (34, 41, 'ORG')]}), ('KDM is Dr. Chandrasekhar, Director of Baycare Heart Failure Clinic.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 24, 'PERSON'), (26, 34, 'DESIGNATION'), (38, 66, 'ORG')]}), ('KDM is Maheash Amin, CV Medical Director for Baycare Medical Group.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 19, 'PERSON'), (24, 40, 'DESIGNATION'), (45, 66, 'ORG')]}), ('Dr. Ballantyne is a cardiologist and Chief of Cardiology, Department of Medicine at Baylor College of Medicine in Houston Texas.', {'entities': [(0, 14, 'PERSON'), (20, 32, 'DESIGNATION'), (46, 56, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (72, 80, 'DEPARTMENT'), (84, 110, 'ORG'), (114, 127, 'GPE')]}), ('The Joslin will adjust any other diabetes medications, if necessary, at that time and complete the PA process if necessary.', {'entities': [(4, 10, 'PERSON'), (33, 41, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (42, 53, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He stated that there will be one more follow up visit at the Joslin and then the patient will be referred back to the Beth Israel Cardiologist.', {'entities': [(118, 129, 'PERSON'), (130, 142, 'DESIGNATION')]}), ('Met with Joseph Zibrak, MD, Chief Pulmonologist at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) in Boston, MA.', {'entities': [(9, 22, 'PERSON'), (28, 47, 'DESIGNATION'), (99, 105, 'GPE')]}), ('Met with Dr. Mark Benson, Director of Preventative Cardiology at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) in Boston, MA.', {'entities': [(9, 17, 'PERSON'), (113, 119, 'GPE')]}), ('Meeting with Lee Gazourian, MD, Pulmonologist and Victoria Theroux, PA at Beth Israel Lahey Health (BILH).', {'entities': [(13, 25, 'PERSON'), (32, 45, 'DESIGNATION'), (50, 66, 'PERSON'), (74, 98, 'ORG'), (100, 104, 'ORG')]}), ('At Diabetes Care event sponsored by Beth Israel Lahey Health (BILH) Health System and Joslin Diabetes Center in Boston, MA.', {'entities': [(112, 118, 'GPE')]}), ('SCE shared that he is aware of several physicians within the Boise State University Health System that once used Spiriva as their LAMA of choice, regardless of COPD severity.', {'entities': [(16, 18, 'PERSON'), (39, 49, 'PERSON'), (61, 83, 'ORG'), (113, 120, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (160, 164, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Met with Zoheir Abdelbaki, MD, Chief of Cardiology/Cardiology Service Line Leader at BonSecours Mercy Health in Lima, OH.', {'entities': [(40, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (85, 108, 'ORG'), (112, 116, 'GPE')]}), ('AC ForumSCE, cardiologist, Boston University School of Medicine, noted that anticoagulants are lifesaving therapies and high risk therapies.', {'entities': [(13, 25, 'DESIGNATION'), (27, 63, 'ORG'), (76, 90, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (106, 115, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Dr. Patorno Epidemiologist in the Division of Pharmacoepidemiology and Pharmacoeconomics at the Brigham and Women's Hospital, stated that in a medicare analysis, SGLT2i's had similar risk of MI, stroke and mortality in patients with CVD as compared to GLP1RA's, but a 24% higher incidence compared to GLP1RAs in patients without CVD.", {'entities': [(0, 11, 'PERSON'), (46, 66, 'DEPARTMENT'), (162, 170, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (191, 193, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (206, 215, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (219, 227, 'PERSON'), (252, 258, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (268, 271, 'PERCENT'), (301, 308, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Dr. Vanita Aroda, Director of Diabetes Clinical Research at the Brigham and Women's Hospital, explained the regulatory guidance on the use of estimands when designing and conducting clinical trials.", {'entities': [(18, 26, 'DESIGNATION'), (30, 56, 'ORG'), (182, 197, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('This SCE is a Endocrinology, Diabetes & Metabolism Specialist at Brody Outpatient Center in Greenville, NC.', {'entities': [(5, 8, 'PERSON'), (14, 27, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (29, 37, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (65, 88, 'ORG'), (92, 102, 'GPE'), (104, 106, 'GPE')]}), ('SCE, Clinical Associate Professor of Medicine at the Brody School of Medicine ECU and Endocrinologist at the V. A. center in Greenville, NC discussed the results of PIONEER 6, specifically CV death and ACM.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (37, 45, 'DEPARTMENT'), (53, 77, 'ORG'), (86, 101, 'PERSON'), (112, 121, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (137, 139, 'GPE'), (173, 174, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('Met with Rachel Ludwig NP with Infinity Medical Hospitalist group for Buffalo General Hospital.', {'entities': [(70, 94, 'ORG')]}), ('SCE is a general cardiologist at Butler Health System in Butler PA.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (9, 29, 'DESIGNATION'), (33, 53, 'ORG')]}), ('Dr. Terence Rhone is the Director of Pulmonogy for CareMore health systems and states that most of his patients with IPF do not belong in a sub-category.', {'entities': [(25, 33, 'DESIGNATION'), (37, 46, 'DEPARTMENT'), (51, 74, 'ORG'), (99, 102, 'PERSON'), (103, 111, 'PERSON'), (117, 120, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (140, 152, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr. Terence Rhone is the Director of Pulmonology for CareMore health systems and is keenly interested in enrolling CareMore patients into nintedanib trials where applicable.', {'entities': [(25, 33, 'DESIGNATION'), (37, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (53, 76, 'ORG'), (124, 132, 'PERSON'), (138, 155, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Dr. C. Noel Bairey Merzis director of the Women's Heart Center at the Cedars-Sinai Heart Institute, where she is a professor of medicine and a pioneer in the study of women's heart health and preventive cardiology.", {'entities': [(70, 98, 'ORG'), (106, 109, 'PERSON'), (115, 124, 'DESIGNATION'), (203, 213, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("The CAMC Clinical Trials Center conducts research with medical device and pharmaceutical companies for the Charleston Area Medical Center and it's practicing physicians.", {'entities': [(107, 137, 'ORG'), (158, 168, 'PEOPLE')]}), ("In a discussion with the SCE, she commented that Dr. Michal Cidron, a pediatric rheumatologist at Children's Hospital of LA is investigating methods of quantifying pediatric ILD on CT.", {'entities': [(98, 123, 'ORG')]}), ('Nancy Konieczny, R. Ph, MBA, Director of Pharmacy, Respiratory, and Research Christian Hospital - BJC St. Louis, MO KDM shared that her hospital generally used nebulizers to administer COPD inhaled medications for patients admitted for exacerbations.', {'entities': [(77, 111, 'ORG'), (214, 222, 'ORG'), (236, 249, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Nancy Konieczny, R. Ph, MBA, Director of Pharmacy, Respiratory, and Research Christian Hospital - BJC St. Louis, MO KDM was recently given leadership responsibility for research at Christian Hospital (however they are no longer doing oncology reseach at this BJC facility - moved to Barnes and Siteman Cancer Center).', {'entities': [(77, 111, 'ORG'), (294, 315, 'ORG')]}), ('Nancy Konieczny, R. Ph, MBA, Director of Pharmacy, Respiratory, and Research Christian Hospital - BJC St. Louis, MO KDM was not aware of the recent Dynagito or IMPACT publications.', {'entities': [(77, 111, 'ORG')]}), ('Nancy Konieczny, R. Ph, MBA, Director of Pharmacy, Respiratory, and Research Christian Hospital - BJC St. Louis, MO The BJC System PT committee uses rotating pharmacy residents to conduct the "deep dive" into clinical data in preparation for System PT formulary reviews.', {'entities': [(77, 111, 'ORG')]}), ('SCE is a pulmonologist and Director of all PFT labs affiliated with the Cleveland Clinic.', {'entities': [(72, 88, 'ORG')]}), ('SCE stated that even in an organized health system i.e., the Cleveland Clinic, only 13% of COPD patients had ever had a PFT performed.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (61, 77, 'ORG'), (96, 104, 'PERSON'), (120, 123, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Interestingly, SCE is meeting this afternoon with the Quality Committee to improve standards around spirometry and implementation of spirometry for the Cleveland Clinic and its wide-reaching affiliates.', {'entities': [(15, 18, 'PERSON'), (152, 168, 'ORG'), (191, 201, 'GPE')]}), ("He has been reading PFT's for Cleveland Clinic Main and multiple other hospitals within the system and disagreed with commercial representation that suboptimal PIF was a relevant issue.", {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (30, 46, 'ORG'), (149, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (160, 163, 'PERSON')]}), ('PSCE is a pulmonologist and Director of all PFT labs affiliated with the Cleveland Clinic.', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (73, 89, 'ORG')]}), ('/ppSCE states that they (Cleveland Clinic Pulms) are beginning to pay closer attention to eosinophil levels to determine appropriate ICS treatment.', {'entities': [(19, 23, 'PERSON'), (25, 41, 'ORG'), (90, 107, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (133, 146, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Met with Bohdan Pichurko, MD, staff pulmonologist and Medical Director of Outpatient PFT labs for the Cleveland Clinic.', {'entities': [(30, 49, 'DESIGNATION'), (54, 70, 'DESIGNATION'), (102, 118, 'ORG')]}), ('AC Forum, Hollywood FLSCE, cardiologist, Cleveland Clinic, noted that PAD is a high CV risk and high mortality disease.', {'entities': [(27, 39, 'DESIGNATION'), (41, 57, 'ORG'), (70, 73, 'ORG'), (101, 118, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Diana Isaacs, PharmD from the Cleveland Clinic presented posted titled "Impact of Physician-Pharmacist Collaboration on A1C in an Interprofessional Endocrinology Clinic".', {'entities': [(30, 46, 'ORG'), (120, 123, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (148, 161, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Shayna Mahapatra, MD from The Cleveland Clinic presented poster titled "Impact of the Cardioprotective Effects of GLP-1 Agonists in the Management of Diabetes".', {'entities': [(30, 46, 'ORG'), (114, 128, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (150, 158, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Met with Diana Isaacs, PharmD, Clinical Pharmacist and Certified Diabetes Educator (CDE) at the Cleveland Clinic Diabetes Center.', {'entities': [(31, 50, 'DESIGNATION'), (96, 128, 'ORG')]}), ('Pharmacist Bonnie LaTourette is Clinical Pharmacist and Preceptor at Community Memorial Hospital in Menomonee Falls, Wisconsin.', {'entities': [(18, 28, 'PERSON'), (69, 96, 'ORG'), (117, 126, 'GPE')]}), ('Cardiology fellow at CPMC stated that she had attended several educational sessions since we last discussed the EMPA-REG data and she has heard very favorable presentations from other speaker physicians during the Mayo Clinic Board Review and CA ACC Annual Session,', {'entities': [(21, 25, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (38, 41, 'PERSON'), (112, 120, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (159, 172, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (184, 191, 'PERSON'), (192, 202, 'PERSON'), (214, 238, 'ORG'), (246, 265, 'PERSON')]}), ('Cardiology fellowfrom CPMC hospital will be giving an educationallectureto physicians titled "Update on Pharmacotherapywith CardiovascularMortality Benefit" with Jardiance being featured prominently.', {'entities': [(22, 35, 'ORG'), (75, 85, 'PERSON'), (124, 155, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (162, 171, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE stated the Creighton University/CHI has just submitted their application to the PFF to receive their PFF center of excellence certification.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (15, 35, 'ORG'), (36, 39, 'ORG'), (84, 87, 'ORG')]}), ('MarieElena Cordisco, Director of Clinical Trials, Department of Research Innovation at Danbury Hospital, the largest facility under the Western Connecticut Health Network, reached out about a meeting with BI CDMA to further discuss the potential for current and future research as a partner.', {'entities': [(33, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (87, 103, 'ORG'), (136, 170, 'ORG'), (205, 212, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM is the director of population health strategy at the Delaware Valley Accountable Care Organization (DVACO).', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (57, 104, 'ORG'), (104, 109, 'ORG')]}), ('KDM is the Pharmacy focused director of population health strategist at the Delaware Valley Accountable Care Organization (DVACO).', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (123, 128, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr. John Buse, Director of Diabetes Care Center at UNC, Chapel Hill, NC.', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (15, 23, 'DESIGNATION'), (27, 47, 'ORG'), (51, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Nancy Rennert, System Medical Director of Diabetes Care, Western Connecticut Health Network, teaches fellows from Yale and University of Vermont College of Medicine.', {'entities': [(0, 13, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (22, 38, 'DESIGNATION'), (42, 55, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (57, 91, 'ORG'), (123, 164, 'ORG')]}), ('SCE is a clinical nephrologist, Associate Medical Director of the Dialysis Clinic, Inc. in Boston, and associate professor at the Tufts University School of Medicine who co-presented "Late Breaking Research Presentations — Exercise and Physical Function in Older Adults with Advanced CKD: The AWARD Randomized Controlled Trial" at NKF SCM 2019.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (9, 30, 'DESIGNATION'), (42, 58, 'DESIGNATION'), (66, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (91, 97, 'GPE'), (113, 122, 'PERSON')]}), ('They are not only using the Duke population to train the program (which most other institutions do) they are using multiple populations for wider applicability.', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (33, 43, 'PERSON'), (100, 104, 'PERSON')]}), ("Dr. David A D'Alessio, MD, Professor of Medicine, Chief, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism and Member of Duke Molecular Physiology Institute.", {'entities': [(0, 9, 'PERSON'), (27, 36, 'DESIGNATION'), (69, 82, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (112, 116, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (117, 126, 'ORG')]}), ('He presented at the Medical College of Wisconsin/Froedtert Health System diabetes symposium.', {'entities': [(73, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that de-escalation of ICS is typically a negotiation that occurs over time as she develops trust with her patient.', {'entities': [(72, 81, 'TIME'), (85, 88, 'PERSON'), (109, 112, 'PERSON'), (113, 120, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE states that she is currently involved in researching comorbidities that overlap with COPD.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 19, 'PERSON'), (57, 70, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (89, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that allergic sensitization and environmental exposure to toxins that may increase prevalence, symptom burden and COPD exacerbations.', {'entities': [(12, 21, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (121, 125, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE hypothesizes that anemic COPD patients may have increased systemic inflammation.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (22, 28, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (29, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (34, 42, 'PERSON'), (62, 83, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE hypothesizes that anemic COPD patients may have increased systemic inflammation', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON')]}), ('States that treating underlying anemia and other cardiovascular comorbidities may improve outcomes in these COPD patients.', {'entities': [(32, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (49, 77, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (108, 112, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (113, 121, 'PERSON')]}), ('Referenced 2019 AACE and ADA as support to start at first line or second line after metformin and said that CVOT hints to being cardio protective.', {'entities': [(11, 20, 'ORG'), (84, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (108, 112, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (128, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("SCE is an Associate Professor of Medicine at John's Hopkins Medical Center in Baltimore, MD. States that the majority of her referrals are from primary care.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'ORG'), (89, 91, 'PERSON'), (121, 124, 'PERSON'), (144, 156, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that she has noticed that recent referrals are typically on triple therapy.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERSON'), (67, 73, 'CARDINAL'), (74, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that 50% of patients she is referred are not candidates for triple therapy.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERCENT'), (27, 31, 'PERSON'), (52, 62, 'PERSON'), (67, 73, 'CARDINAL'), (74, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that she attempts to de-escalate ICS therapy when appropriate, but often is challenged by patients, as patients are often reluctant to remove medications from their maintenance regimen.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERSON'), (40, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (110, 118, 'PERSON'), (149, 160, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that she is specifically researching environmental association with comorbidities that foster allergic response or atopy in COPD.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERSON'), (75, 88, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (101, 109, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (122, 127, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (131, 135, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States she is exploring environmental exposure outcomes in COPD.', {'entities': [(7, 10, 'PERSON'), (59, 63, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that she is researching the effects of anemia in COPD.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERSON'), (46, 52, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (56, 60, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that COPD patients with anemia typically experience increased symptoms such as dyspnea, limited exercise capacity, etc.', {'entities': [(12, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (17, 25, 'PERSON'), (31, 37, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that COPD patients with polycythemia do not experience that same level of functional decline.', {'entities': [(12, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (17, 25, 'PERSON'), (31, 43, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE states that Johns Hopkins does not routinely assess PIFR in COPD.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 29, 'ORG'), (56, 60, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (64, 68, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that she thinks that Johns Hopkins should consider assessing PIFR with the InCheck Device.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERSON'), (28, 41, 'ORG'), (68, 72, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (82, 96, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that Johns Hopkins is currently starting a "precision medicine center."', {'entities': [(12, 25, 'ORG'), (51, 77, 'ORG')]}), ("States that when HCP's access PIFR that it is usually in COPD patients that are experiencing difficulty with symptoms, exacerbations, and a lack of efficacy from maintenance medications.", {'entities': [(17, 20, 'PERSON'), (30, 34, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (57, 61, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (62, 70, 'PERSON'), (174, 185, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that most of her patients have difficulty with activating a pMDI due to a lack of hand strength needed to actuate the pMDI.', {'entities': [(20, 23, 'PERSON'), (24, 32, 'PERSON'), (67, 71, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (125, 129, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that coordination between actuation and inhalation timing is a frequent error that she observes in her patients.', {'entities': [(47, 57, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (70, 78, 'TIME'), (90, 93, 'PERSON'), (106, 109, 'PERSON'), (110, 118, 'PERSON')]}), ('States that inhaler education at Johns Hopkins, is typically conducted by nursing staff.', {'entities': [(12, 19, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (33, 46, 'ORG'), (74, 87, 'PERSON')]}), ('States that the lack of medication adherence in her patients is a major concern.', {'entities': [(24, 34, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (48, 51, 'PERSON'), (52, 60, 'PERSON')]}), ('States that another source of frustration is when she prescribes a specific medication, and due to a patients insurance, the pharmacy substitutes for another medication with a different inhaler.', {'entities': [(49, 53, 'PERSON'), (76, 86, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (101, 109, 'PERSON'), (125, 133, 'ORG'), (158, 168, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (186, 193, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that her patients typically receive not inhaler education from pharmacies.', {'entities': [(12, 15, 'PERSON'), (16, 24, 'PERSON'), (47, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (70, 80, 'ORG')]}), ('Paresh Dandona, MD, PhD, SUNY Distinguished Professor, Chief of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, SUNY at Buffalo Founder and Director, Diabetes and Endocrinology Center of Western New York presented Are We Waiting too Long to Start GLP-1 RA in Adult Patients with T2DM? Presentation was a non-CME lunch symposium at the Cleveland Clinic 24th Annual Diabetes Day and was a promotional program for Ozempic sponsored by Novo Nordisk.', {'entities': [(0, 14, 'PERSON'), (44, 53, 'PERSON'), (64, 77, 'DEPARTMENT'), (104, 119, 'ORG'), (120, 127, 'PERSON'), (132, 140, 'PERSON'), (142, 175, 'ORG'), (179, 195, 'GPE'), (239, 247, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (251, 265, 'PERSON'), (271, 275, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (296, 303, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (327, 343, 'ORG'), (403, 410, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (424, 437, 'ORG')]}), ('All adverse events related to GLP-1 RA were reviewed and he suggested starting on lower dose and not increasing too fast to avoid risk of retinopathy.', {'entities': [(29, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (57, 59, 'PERSON'), (82, 92, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (137, 149, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Stated that pancreatitis was added because of one person had seen it in clinical practice and pursued the FDA to add but has not been seen as a safety signal in clinical trials.', {'entities': [(12, 24, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (50, 56, 'PERSON'), (72, 89, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (106, 109, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (161, 176, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Speaker referenced the GI side effects and study dropout rates and stated he has a low incidence of discontinuation in his practice.', {'entities': [(0, 7, 'PERSON'), (23, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (74, 76, 'PERSON'), (119, 122, 'PERSON')]}), ('Speaker discussed liraglutide as the first GLP-1 RA that worked 24 hours and had MOA other than on b-cell to improve glucose control in T1DM.', {'entities': [(0, 7, 'PERSON'), (18, 29, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (37, 42, 'CARDINAL'), (43, 52, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (64, 72, 'TIME'), (81, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (99, 105, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (117, 124, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 140, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Stated lira provided more predictability in blood sugars for patients as well as decrease in post-prandial insulin dose and decrease in body weight and shown to have glucagon suppression.', {'entities': [(7, 11, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (44, 56, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (61, 69, 'PERSON'), (93, 106, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (107, 119, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (166, 174, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Shared that lira has shown the potential to be insulin sensitizing due to decrease in inflammatory cells and Novo investigating the decrease in SBP and the RAS.', {'entities': [(12, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (47, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (55, 66, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 104, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (109, 113, 'ORG'), (144, 147, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (156, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Stated A1c reduction is modest but QOL of patient is improved due to the predictability of blood sugars.', {'entities': [(7, 10, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (35, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (42, 49, 'PERSON'), (91, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Presented quoted a JDRF study not yet published that is investigating lira in obese T1DM subjects which has demonstrated a significant decrease in weight, body fat (while maintaining lean muscle mass) which could provide a novel approach to obesity.', {'entities': [(19, 23, 'ORG'), (70, 74, 'ORG'), (84, 88, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (155, 163, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (183, 199, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (241, 248, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('An additional small GLP-1 RA study was referenced in C-peptide positive T1DM patients that showed islet preservation and decreased b-cell apoptosis and that 5/10 patients were able to go off insulin.', {'entities': [(20, 28, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (53, 62, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (72, 76, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (77, 85, 'PERSON'), (98, 116, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (131, 147, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (157, 161, 'CARDINAL'), (162, 170, 'PERSON'), (191, 198, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Presenter went on to discuss the results of DEPICT 1 and 2 as well as Triple Therapy in Type 1 Diabetes (Insulin plus GLP-1 plus SGLT-2 Inhibitor dapagliflozin).', {'entities': [(0, 9, 'PERSON'), (44, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (51, 52, 'CARDINAL'), (57, 58, 'CARDINAL'), (70, 76, 'CARDINAL'), (77, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (88, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (105, 117, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (118, 128, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (129, 135, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (146, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The hypothesis would be to investigate if triple therapy could further improve glucose control in T1DM and since liraglutide suppresses glucagon and lowers FFA while SGLT-2 inhibitors increase glucagon and risk of DKA, is it possible that the combination of the two agents may neutralize the DKA risk.', {'entities': [(42, 48, 'CARDINAL'), (49, 56, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (79, 86, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (98, 102, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (113, 124, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 144, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (156, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (166, 172, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (173, 183, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (193, 201, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (214, 217, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (262, 265, 'CARDINAL'), (292, 295, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The investigators conclusions were: 1. the addition of dapagliflozin (10mg/day) to insulin and liraglutide in T1D results in a significant improvement in glycemia as reflected in both HbA1c and glucose concentrations along with significant weight loss 2.', {'entities': [(4, 17, 'PERSON'), (36, 37, 'CARDINAL'), (55, 68, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (70, 72, 'CARDINAL'), (83, 90, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (95, 106, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (110, 113, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (154, 162, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (184, 189, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (194, 201, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (202, 216, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (252, 253, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('There is also a concomitant increase in plasma glucagon concentrations, lipolysis and FFA, which provides the substrate for ketogenesis, with an increase in acetoacetate and b-hydroxybutyrate concentrations 3.', {'entities': [(40, 55, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (72, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 89, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (110, 119, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (124, 135, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (157, 169, 'CHEMICAL_COMPOUND'), (174, 191, 'CHEMICAL_COMPOUND'), (207, 208, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('The increase in glucagon and FFA by dapagliflozin occurred in spite of the presence of liraglutide, which was shown to suppress both 4.', {'entities': [(16, 24, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (29, 32, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (36, 49, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (87, 98, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (133, 134, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('Achieved insulin doses are adequate to manage glycemia but it may not be sufficient to adequately perform its other physiological functions including suppression of lipolysis and ketogenesis 5.', {'entities': [(9, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (46, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (116, 129, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (165, 174, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (179, 190, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (191, 192, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('The increased lipolysis in association with low insulin doses may increase the risk of DKA. (Kuhadiya ND, Ghanim H, Mehta A, Garg M, Khan S, et al. (2016) Dapagliflozin as Additional Treatment to Liraglutide and Insulin in Patients With Type 1 Diabetes.', {'entities': [(14, 23, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (48, 55, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (87, 90, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (93, 104, 'PERSON'), (106, 114, 'PERSON'), (116, 123, 'PERSON'), (125, 131, 'PERSON'), (133, 139, 'PERSON'), (149, 153, 'CARDINAL'), (155, 168, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (183, 192, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (196, 207, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (212, 219, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (223, 231, 'PERSON'), (237, 252, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Aidar R. Gosmanov, MD, Ph. D, Professor of Endocrinology at Albany Medical College in Albany, NY, presented ePoster 1117-P "Metformin Increases Blood Lactic Acid Levels in Elderly Diabetic Veterans with Stage 3 CKD, " which showed results of an expected increase in lactic acid production in patients with worsening renal function.', {'entities': [(0, 17, 'PERSON'), (30, 39, 'PERSON'), (43, 56, 'DEPARTMENT'), (60, 82, 'ORG'), (86, 93, 'GPE'), (116, 120, 'CARDINAL'), (124, 133, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (144, 161, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (180, 197, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (203, 214, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (266, 277, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (292, 300, 'PERSON'), (316, 330, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Interestingly, SCE displayed even if you perform a 50% dose reduction in metformin in patients with stage 3 CKD, after 6 months of therapy of the lower dose, you will observe similar HbA1C reduction (vs. full dose metformin) with a statistically significant reduction in lactic acid levels in the lower dose reduction group (LA 3.8 mmol/L vs. LA 1.5 mmol/L, respectively).', {'entities': [(15, 18, 'PERSON'), (51, 54, 'PERCENT'), (73, 82, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 94, 'PERSON'), (100, 111, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (119, 120, 'CARDINAL'), (183, 188, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (214, 223, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (271, 282, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (328, 331, 'CARDINAL'), (346, 349, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('This information presented can provide added support for use of empagliflozin in CKD patients or for empagliflozin consideration in patients intolerant to metformin.', {'entities': [(64, 77, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (81, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (85, 93, 'PERSON'), (101, 114, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (132, 140, 'PERSON'), (155, 164, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('DKA data not provided. Poster attached here: https://ada. apprisor. org/epsView. cfm?bf15R5f1AwzLvnTjvTWY61tozMdAWpd%2BC2FY%2BZZjzE3nAh8BUudouEwwyST7CbPpUQdPoIGJjeY%3D (JN/ 6/8/19)', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE is a cardiologist that specializes in Advanced Heart Failure at Allegheny General Hospital in Pittsburgh, PA.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (9, 21, 'PERSON'), (42, 64, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (68, 94, 'ORG'), (98, 108, 'GPE')]}), ('She is a co-investigator of the dapagliflozin HF clinical trial program. She states that patient enrollment and study participation has been completed at her practice site.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (9, 24, 'DESIGNATION'), (32, 45, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (46, 71, 'EVENT'), (73, 76, 'PERSON'), (89, 96, 'PERSON'), (154, 157, 'PERSON')]}), ('In an unsolicited manner, she mentioned that she was not sold on the data from the COMPASS trial for rivaroxaban.', {'entities': [(26, 29, 'PERSON'), (45, 48, 'PERSON'), (83, 96, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (101, 112, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('She thinks you need to carefully weigh the risk vs. benefit before deciding to use very-low dose rivaroxaban in combination with aspirin in patients with stable CAD in clinical practice.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (11, 14, 'PERSON'), (97, 108, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (129, 136, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (140, 148, 'PERSON'), (161, 164, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (168, 185, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('HCP is a clinical pharmacist at the Allegheny Health Network Wexford Health and Wellness Pavilion in Wexford, PA. In an unsolicited manner, she expressed interest in the empagliflozin dedicated renal study.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (9, 28, 'DESIGNATION'), (36, 97, 'ORG'), (101, 108, 'GPE'), (140, 144, 'PERSON'), (170, 183, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (194, 205, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("As the clinical pharmacist working with prescribers, she is often responsible for monitoring patients' renal function and making dose adjustments.", {'entities': [(7, 26, 'DESIGNATION'), (40, 51, 'PERSON'), (53, 56, 'PERSON'), (93, 101, 'PERSON'), (103, 117, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('She states that she is aware of the labeled eGFR cutoff of 45 for empagliflozin, but is also aware that the inclusion criteria in ERO went down to an eGFR of 30.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 19, 'PERSON'), (44, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (59, 61, 'CARDINAL'), (66, 79, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (130, 133, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (150, 154, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (158, 160, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('She mentions that it will be helpful if EMPA-KIDNEY can answer whether empagliflozin is safe and effective to use in patients with an eGFR that falls below 45, as this does occur in clinical practice.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (40, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (71, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (117, 125, 'PERSON'), (134, 138, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (156, 158, 'CARDINAL'), (182, 199, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He stated that he bases his decision to initiate antifibrotics in patients with IPF based on the patient\'s "physiologic" age.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (15, 17, 'PERSON'), (23, 27, 'PERSON'), (49, 62, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (66, 74, 'PERSON'), (80, 83, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (97, 106, 'PERSON'), (108, 119, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He gave no specific definition of "physiologic" aâ‰¥ however, he used an example of two 75 year old patients.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (35, 46, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (60, 62, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (82, 85, 'CARDINAL'), (86, 88, 'CARDINAL'), (98, 106, 'PERSON')]}), ('One patient is frail with multiple comorbidities and the other is relatively healthy.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'CARDINAL'), (4, 11, 'PERSON'), (35, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (77, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He would not initiate antifibrotics in the frail patient and would in the latter patient who was relatively healthy.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (22, 35, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (49, 56, 'PERSON'), (81, 88, 'PERSON'), (108, 115, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He stated that his practice co-manages patients with CTD-ILD with Rheumatology; however, the pulmonologist often makes the decision on what medication to use.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (15, 18, 'PERSON'), (19, 27, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (39, 47, 'PERSON'), (53, 60, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (66, 78, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (93, 106, 'DESIGNATION'), (140, 150, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Cyclophosphamide and MMF are both used; however, the pulmonologists are concerned with the side effects of both medications.', {'entities': [(0, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (21, 24, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (53, 68, 'PERSON')]}), ("He believes that regardless of the cause, fibrosis has a common pathway, and he feels that Nintedanib should work in multiple ILD's due to its mechanism of action.", {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (42, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (91, 101, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (126, 131, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that primary care physicians always prescribe Advair to COPD patients without assessing if the patient is appropriate for ICS therapy.', {'entities': [(12, 24, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (25, 35, 'PERSON'), (53, 59, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (63, 67, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (68, 76, 'PERSON'), (102, 109, 'PERSON'), (129, 140, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States additional education is needed in primary care. States he believes that a COPD clinical educator would be welcomed by this specialty.', {'entities': [(41, 53, 'ORG'), (62, 64, 'PERSON'), (81, 85, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 103, 'PERSON')]}), ('States that pharmacists are not educated properly in inhaler education. States that there is training for pharmacists in NY on inhaler technique, but feels that inhaler education is not routinely performed by pharmacists.', {'entities': [(12, 23, 'PERSON'), (53, 60, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (106, 117, 'PERSON'), (121, 123, 'GPE'), (127, 144, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (161, 168, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (209, 220, 'PERSON')]}), ('States that inhaler education at AMC is performed in-house. States that his staff is skilled at inhaler education, and ensure that his patients are educated on all prescribed inhalers.', {'entities': [(12, 19, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (33, 36, 'ORG'), (72, 75, 'PERSON'), (76, 81, 'PERSON'), (96, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (131, 134, 'PERSON'), (135, 143, 'PERSON'), (164, 174, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (175, 183, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("SCE believes that suboptimal PIFR is a concern for patient utilizing DPI's. SCE does not utilize the InCheck device to access PIFR.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (18, 28, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (29, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (51, 58, 'PERSON'), (69, 74, 'PERSON'), (76, 79, 'PERSON'), (101, 115, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (126, 130, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('His main hesitation in intiating therapy is that SGLT2 inhibitors is looked upon as a diabetes agent within his system and does not want to step on the toes of primary care and endocrinology.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (33, 40, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (49, 65, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 100, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (108, 111, 'PERSON'), (160, 172, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (177, 190, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He has a wealth of knowledge about BI product usage in his clinical practice and he is practicing in the northshore of Massachusetts, so he could speak in that area as well as southeastern New Hampshire and southern Maine where we have no KEEs currently.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (59, 76, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (81, 83, 'PERSON'), (105, 115, 'LOC'), (119, 132, 'GPE'), (137, 139, 'PERSON'), (176, 188, 'LOC'), (189, 202, 'GPE'), (207, 216, 'LOC'), (216, 221, 'GPE')]}), ('Dr. Kim, Pulmonologist at Anna Jacques Hospital in Newburyport, Mass. with a large out-patient practice, let me know last wek that he had seen the Lancet Article, was going to read it and we could discuss.', {'entities': [(0, 7, 'PERSON'), (9, 22, 'DESIGNATION'), (26, 47, 'ORG'), (51, 62, 'GPE'), (83, 94, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (95, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (109, 111, 'PERSON'), (117, 125, 'TIME'), (131, 133, 'PERSON'), (147, 161, 'WORK_OF_ART'), (188, 190, 'PERSON')]}), ('He has done it when eosinophil levels and, more importantly, clinical aspects of the patient - improved PFTs, QOLs have improved.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (20, 37, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (61, 69, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (85, 92, 'PERSON'), (104, 108, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (110, 114, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He called, today, Aprll 13th and here\'s his feedback: 1.) When asked for his initial thoughts: He responded first by asking "How is BI looking at the study", then added that to him as a clinical pulmonologist, "I think I need more data and or clinical experience" to make a better decision on the trial results.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (11, 16, 'DATE'), (18, 28, 'DATE'), (40, 43, 'PERSON'), (73, 76, 'PERSON'), (95, 97, 'PERSON'), (177, 180, 'PERSON'), (186, 208, 'DESIGNATION'), (243, 251, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He said that there were many good things in regard to the size of the patient pool, the length of the study and the numerical results, yet he mentioned that without a washout period of significant time and results/discussion regarding patients on ICS or not on ICS and/or antibiotics still left some doubt in his mind', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (70, 77, 'PERSON'), (139, 141, 'PERSON'), (185, 201, 'TIME'), (235, 243, 'PERSON'), (247, 250, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (261, 264, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (272, 283, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (309, 312, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He called, today, Aprll 13th and here\'s his feedback: Overall feedback - He said that the 0.01 primary endpoint "seemed quite aggressive to me", but "the p=value of 0.498 was good and would have met most other trial statistical endpoints".', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (11, 16, 'DATE'), (18, 28, 'DATE'), (40, 43, 'PERSON'), (73, 75, 'PERSON'), (140, 142, 'PERSON'), (165, 170, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('We discussed the reason for the 99%CI and the reason to go with that and that this trial did not meet it; and Dr. Kim said that he understood the rational and that he was "impressed with such a large patient population and the duration period of the trial.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (32, 37, 'PERCENT'), (110, 117, 'PERSON'), (128, 130, 'PERSON'), (164, 166, 'PERSON'), (200, 207, 'PERSON'), (208, 218, 'PERSON'), (227, 242, 'DATE')]}), ('And, he did say that knowing Spiriva was indicated for exacerbations and having this body of evidence gave him more confidence in writing Stiolto.', {'entities': [(5, 7, 'PERSON'), (29, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (107, 110, 'PERSON'), (138, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('This SCE likes to prescribe DPP4i in the elderly populationdue to no renal adjustments. Linagliptin is the preferred agent, especially in ESRD.', {'entities': [(5, 8, 'PERSON'), (28, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (49, 59, 'PERSON'), (69, 74, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (88, 99, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (117, 122, 'PERSON'), (138, 142, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("GLP-1's have a greater weight loss benefit, provides a good A1C reduction of 1.0 â€” 1.5%, increases in pharmaceutical compliance because of its once weekly injections, the side effects of nausea will reside eventually, and positive CV outcome.", {'entities': [(0, 7, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (60, 63, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (77, 80, 'CARDINAL'), (83, 87, 'PERCENT'), (102, 116, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (143, 154, 'TIME'), (155, 165, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (171, 184, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (187, 193, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (231, 241, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("This endocrinology expert states they use SGLT2i's when patient refuses an injectable. If the patient has a history of heart failure, consulting with HF physician would be a step to consider beforeinitiating a SGLT2i.", {'entities': [(5, 25, 'PERSON'), (33, 37, 'PERSON'), (42, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (56, 63, 'PERSON'), (75, 85, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (94, 101, 'PERSON'), (119, 132, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (134, 144, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (150, 162, 'PERSON'), (210, 216, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('When I initiate the SGLT2i the following actions are completed: check renal function, if eGFR 45 - will not initiate, adjust the HTN meds (with or without cardiology input), educate patient ifNPO or with a GI bug causing emesis, hold SGLT2i that day, if urine dark yellow, increase fluid intake to prevent kidney injury, anduse baby wipes or barrier cream to keep genital area clean, to avoidthe risk of genital infections.', {'entities': [(5, 6, 'PERSON'), (20, 26, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (70, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (89, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (94, 96, 'CARDINAL'), (129, 137, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (155, 165, 'DEPARTMENT'), (182, 189, 'PERSON')]}), ('This SCE states that rising costs of medications is becoming the #1 reason of why some patients have a positive clinical outcome vs those who do not.', {'entities': [(5, 8, 'PERSON'), (37, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (65, 67, 'CARDINAL'), (87, 95, 'PERSON'), (112, 128, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Over 24% of T2DM patients skipped filling their medication because of cost, followed by skipping a schedule does, taking expired medication, cutting pills in half, and sharing prescriptions.', {'entities': [(5, 8, 'PERCENT'), (12, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (17, 25, 'PERSON'), (48, 58, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (129, 139, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (149, 154, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (176, 189, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The government needs to intervene and help come up with a solution of how to providesome kind ofplan forall individuals to have access todiabetes medications, in particular.', {'entities': [(108, 119, 'PERSON'), (137, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (146, 157, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('All processes, such as, PBM, insurance companies, along withthe pharmaceutical companies are liable and need to be address.', {'entities': [(24, 27, 'ORG'), (29, 48, 'ORG'), (64, 88, 'ORG')]}), ('Dr. Goran Rudic, MD is internist at Ascension Health System in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. KDM requested Medical support for information around empagliflozin vs canagliflozin and electrolyte disturbances.', {'entities': [(0, 15, 'PERSON'), (23, 32, 'DESIGNATION'), (36, 59, 'ORG'), (63, 72, 'GPE'), (74, 83, 'GPE'), (85, 88, 'PERSON'), (99, 114, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (138, 151, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (155, 168, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (173, 184, 'CHEMICAL_TERM')]}), ('Interested in seeing more how empagliflozin may be used in combination with GLP1s with respect to A1C efficacy, changes in CV profile, and other potential beneficial impacts. Believes this would be a good study to undertake.', {'entities': [(30, 43, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (76, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (98, 110, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM states he thought there were differences between empagliflozin and canagliflozin with respect to electrolyte disturbances.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (11, 13, 'PERSON'), (53, 66, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (71, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (101, 112, 'CHEMICAL_TERM')]}), ('Inquired about information that could shed additional light on this topic. Will reach out to MTCI for more specific information.', {'entities': [(93, 97, 'ORG')]}), ('Initial meeting with Cheryl Habeck, NP, who practices at Ascension Medical Clinic, Menasha, WI. I was invited to present finding of ERO and address any off-label questions if they arose.', {'entities': [(21, 34, 'PERSON'), (44, 53, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (57, 81, 'ORG'), (83, 90, 'GPE'), (96, 97, 'PERSON'), (132, 135, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (175, 179, 'PERSON')]}), ('2. Reconfirmed KDMs knowledge around ERO and the CV findings in the trial.', {'entities': [(15, 19, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (37, 40, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (49, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('3. Formulary access to Empagliflozin can be a challenge as it is prior authorized by Ascension Health Plan.', {'entities': [(23, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (85, 106, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("4. Inquired about the incidence of Fournier's gangrene and also necrotizing fascititis. See this is a very limited AE especially in light of the CV benefit empagliflozin offer. Provided the incidence of FG/NF in the pooled data for empagliflozin. Will follow-up with MTCI or approved e-mail as a formal response.", {'entities': [(35, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (76, 86, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (115, 117, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (145, 147, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (156, 169, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (203, 208, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (232, 245, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (267, 271, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("When the ATP is more efficient, the heart doesn't have to work as hard to maintain the output it needs to do according to whatever health state the body is in, especially in a HF specimen.", {'entities': [(9, 12, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (36, 41, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (131, 143, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (176, 187, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('This pharmaceutical management could be applied to using empa earlier in the injury state i.e., post MI to prevent the heart from entering into a remodeling heart failure syndrome state".', {'entities': [(5, 30, 'ORG'), (57, 61, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (101, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (119, 124, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (157, 185, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('That is, although COPD disease management and AECOPD are a high priority within the health system, the challenge to address and then transition to value based care (patient centric) is due to conflict between population health, pharmacy, and clinicians.', {'entities': [(17, 41, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (46, 52, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (84, 97, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (165, 180, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (228, 236, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (242, 252, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Initial meeting with Dr. Kariuki, Ngaruiya, MD endocrinologist at Aurora Sheboygan clinic. Dr. Ngaruiya is new to the practice being there for the past six months.', {'entities': [(21, 32, 'PERSON'), (34, 42, 'PERSON'), (47, 62, 'PERSON'), (66, 89, 'ORG'), (91, 103, 'PERSON'), (118, 126, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (152, 162, 'DATE')]}), ("Per the clinic's request, I provided an update on the current practice guidelines, review of ERO, update on Emprise and also answered any questions.", {'entities': [(8, 16, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (62, 70, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (93, 96, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (108, 115, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Insights gained from Dr. Ngaruiya: RWE: KDM finds Emprise data very encouraging with respect to initial HF outcomes.', {'entities': [(21, 33, 'PERSON'), (40, 43, 'PERSON'), (50, 57, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (104, 115, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Believes HF will be an important issue to address moving forward in patients at highest risk.', {'entities': [(9, 11, 'PERSON'), (68, 76, 'PERSON')]}), ('Dr. Ngaruiya is new to the practice being there for the past six months.', {'entities': [(0, 12, 'PERSON'), (27, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (61, 71, 'DATE')]}), ('R: reiterated that the 10mg and the 25mg lower A1C similarly, and it is really patient specific in terms of dose response. With respect to CVOT, the data show similar outcomes with respect to 3P MACE.', {'entities': [(23, 27, 'CARDINAL'), (36, 40, 'CARDINAL'), (47, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (79, 86, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (108, 121, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (139, 143, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (192, 199, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Believes the data for Empa is better than the other. Believes this is especially relevant in some older T2D patients that may have osteopenia or osteoporosis. Monitors these patients closely.', {'entities': [(22, 26, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (104, 116, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (131, 141, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (145, 157, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (174, 182, 'PERSON')]}), ("Insights gained from Dr. Ngaruiya: Safety: Requested an update in Fornier's Gangrene and Necrotizing Fasciitis, states that this one the main concerns as to why patients do not want to use SGLT2s.", {'entities': [(21, 33, 'PERSON'), (66, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (89, 110, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (161, 169, 'PERSON'), (189, 195, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Inquired is this was currently a Black Box Warning in the label. Appropriate response provided - no it is not. States patients often use this as a determinant of therapy choice vs injectable therapy.', {'entities': [(33, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (118, 126, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (162, 169, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (180, 198, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('R: Provided information from the label and the potential risk factors that can lead to DKA. Will follow-up with the appropriate literature in Veeva if available.', {'entities': [(87, 90, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (142, 147, 'ORG')]}), ('Insights gained from Dr. Ngaruiya: Efficacy: KDM inquired as to what the kidney outcomes were for Empa relative to the other drugs in the class.', {'entities': [(21, 33, 'PERSON'), (45, 48, 'PERSON'), (73, 88, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (98, 102, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (125, 130, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('R: Reviewed renal data from ERO and the respective outcome, discussed EMPA Kidney trial and design, anticipate read out date, and sub analysis conducted for Empa for this EP. Will follow-up with additional information per this request.', {'entities': [(11, 22, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (28, 31, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (75, 98, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (157, 161, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (171, 173, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Insights gained from Dr. Ngaruiya: Efficacy and Product Selection: 1. Asked KDM how he approached the treatment of a high risk Cardio-metabolic patient?', {'entities': [(21, 33, 'PERSON'), (76, 79, 'PERSON'), (84, 86, 'PERSON'), (102, 111, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (127, 143, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (144, 151, 'PERSON')]}), ('KDM indicates that he applies a Shared Decision making approach with his patients. In patients with established ASCVD, either a SGLT2 or a GLP1 is selected depending on factors like: 1) Need for significant weight loss -- prefer GLP1.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (19, 21, 'PERSON'), (32, 63, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (69, 72, 'PERSON'), (73, 81, 'PERSON'), (86, 94, 'PERSON'), (112, 117, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (139, 143, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (183, 185, 'CARDINAL'), (229, 233, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('.2) Needle phobia or apprehension -- SGLT2 (does prefer empa over cana and dapa, currently).', {'entities': [(4, 17, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (37, 42, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('3) Probability of developing a mycotic infection (history of or poor hygiene habits/uncircumcised male --- GLP1)', {'entities': [(0, 1, 'CARDINAL'), (31, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (69, 76, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (107, 111, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Insights gained from Dr. Ngaruiya: Competitive Intelligence: KDM sees oral semaglutide as a "Clinical Game Changer" is the outcomes (glycemic, CV and renal), safety profile and cost are in a favorable range.', {'entities': [(21, 33, 'PERSON'), (61, 64, 'PERSON'), (75, 86, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (93, 114, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (133, 141, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (143, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (150, 155, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Collectively, this appears to be a very favorable compound in an oral dosasge form.', {'entities': [(50, 58, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (65, 77, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('They requested an update on 2019 Gold Guidelines and PIFR. They are beginning to do proactive intervention with their COPD patients to reduce readmissions in the population.', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (28, 37, 'EVENT'), (53, 57, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (59, 63, 'PERSON'), (112, 117, 'PERSON'), (118, 131, 'PERSON'), (161, 172, 'PERSON')]}), ('They feel that GOLD Guidelines would help in providing guidance in treatment and follow up and that PIFR is an interesting measure that could have some consequences in exacerbations and possible readmissions.', {'entities': [(15, 19, 'EVENT'), (67, 76, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (100, 104, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He asked what the ACC and ADA guidelines are saying about the treatment of these patients. We review the guideline statements.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (18, 29, 'EVENT'), (62, 71, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (81, 89, 'PERSON'), (91, 93, 'PERSON')]}), ('He later asked to have the ACC Consensus Decision Pathway. Dr J sees the benefit of SGLT2s in this patient type.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (27, 30, 'EVENT'), (59, 63, 'PERSON'), (84, 90, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (99, 106, 'PERSON')]}), ('KDM is Petra Estep, PharmD. Clinical pharmacy coordinator for Baptist Health. During an empa clinical pipeline discussion, we discussed in patient formulary status.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 18, 'PERSON'), (28, 57, 'DESIGNATION'), (62, 76, 'ORG'), (88, 110, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (123, 125, 'PERSON'), (139, 146, 'PERSON')]}), ('With all the data and robust clinical pipeline she sees the potential to compete in same position as Entresto. That being said, states it would need to also be backed by inpatient use data.', {'entities': [(47, 50, 'PERSON'), (101, 109, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (170, 179, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Even if pulled retrospectively. Recognizes early separation in outcome curves but needs additional data to justify starting patients for 1-2 days in acute care setting.', {'entities': [(124, 132, 'PERSON'), (137, 145, 'DATE'), (149, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM is Petra Estep, PharmD. Clinical pharmacy coordinator for Baptist Health.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 18, 'PERSON'), (28, 57, 'DESIGNATION'), (62, 76, 'ORG')]}), ('In meeting with her, attempted to gain additional insight as to how she values RWE and were it is positioned in decision influence.', {'entities': [(16, 19, 'PERSON'), (68, 71, 'PERSON'), (79, 82, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that aggressively powered RCT is still gold standard. She places emphasis on the ability of solid RWE to validate RCT and translate into real clinical practice.', {'entities': [(33, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (61, 64, 'PERSON'), (105, 108, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (121, 124, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (149, 166, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The most important thing in RWE for her is patient matching and cohort size. It has the ability to tell a compelling story if cohort is extremely large and matching is aggressive.', {'entities': [(28, 31, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (36, 39, 'PERSON'), (43, 50, 'PERSON')]}), ('Many system wide in-house initiatives that are conducted using RWE are to small and matching is not subtle to have clinical impact.', {'entities': [(63, 66, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (115, 130, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Drs. Shah and Akturk are Assistant Professors of Pediatrics and Medicine at the Barbara Davis Center for Diabetes at the University of Colorado.', {'entities': [(0, 9, 'PERSON'), (14, 20, 'PERSON'), (25, 45, 'DESIGNATION'), (49, 72, 'DEPARTMENT'), (80, 100, 'ORG'), (105, 113, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (120, 143, 'ORG')]}), ('At a meeting with CDMA (ADA 2019), they presented their idea for the development of a DKA risk factor assessment calculator for the use of SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with T1D.', {'entities': [(18, 22, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (35, 39, 'PERSON'), (50, 55, 'PERSON'), (86, 89, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (139, 155, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (159, 167, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (173, 176, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("They are interested in using BI's database of DKA patients for analysis.", {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (29, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (46, 49, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (50, 58, 'PERSON')]}), ('Barnes oncology service recently initiated a new multidisciplinary investigational studies oncology committee with the goal of improving protocol adherence through increased education and communication to the inpatient interdisciplinary care delivery team.', {'entities': [(0, 23, 'ORG'), (91, 99, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (209, 218, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (219, 255, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The committee was started in large part due to requests from an oncology nurse (Ginn) for nurses to gain a better understanding of investigational studies (the purpose of the study, the protocols, and the science behind the studies).', {'entities': [(64, 78, 'PERSON'), (80, 84, 'PERSON'), (90, 96, 'PERSON')]}), ('2) reduction in protocol violations (i.e., avoidance of medication exclusions/protocol violations),', {'entities': [(56, 77, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('3) improved staging documentation of drug reactions (new Epic system will play a role). Amanda Wilson, MD, Inpatient Research Supervisor chairs the new committee.', {'entities': [(37, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (88, 101, 'PERSON'), (107, 136, 'PERSON')]}), ('Two nurse representatives (day/night) from each of the four oncology units (Onc ICU, Med Onc Floor, Allogenic Transplant Floor, and Autologous Transplant Floor) are committee members along with Oncology Pharm. Ds, and other ancillary HCPs.', {'entities': [(4, 9, 'PERSON'), (55, 59, 'CARDINAL'), (60, 74, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (75, 83, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (85, 98, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (100, 126, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (131, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (194, 202, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (203, 212, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (224, 238, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Charge nurses from the committee disseminate information from the studies to oncology floor nurses as needed each shift and round with the oncologists.', {'entities': [(7, 13, 'PERSON'), (77, 85, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (92, 98, 'PERSON'), (139, 150, 'PERSON')]}), ('Amanda Wilson reports up to: John Dispersio, MD Oncologist (email: jdipersi@wustl. edu) Acting Medical Director Oncology Professor of Oncology, Washington University President of ASBMT Board Member of ASBMT Board Member of National Cancer Society', {'entities': [(0, 13, 'PERSON'), (29, 43, 'PERSON'), (48, 58, 'DEPARTMENT'), (95, 111, 'DESIGNATION'), (112, 130, 'DESIGNATION'), (134, 142, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (144, 165, 'ORG'), (166, 175, 'DESIGNATION'), (179, 184, 'ORG'), (185, 197, 'PERSON'), (200, 206, 'PERSON'), (207, 219, 'DESIGNATION'), (223, 246, 'ORG')]}), ('In speaking to the many clinical benefits that he believes empa to have in his patients, he goes on to state that it is the one therapy above all others they are on where you can visual see patient improvement, as well as, patients provide feedback as to overall feeling better.', {'entities': [(24, 41, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (47, 49, 'PERSON'), (59, 63, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (75, 78, 'PERSON'), (79, 87, 'PERSON'), (89, 91, 'PERSON'), (124, 127, 'CARDINAL'), (128, 135, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (153, 157, 'PERSON'), (190, 197, 'PERSON'), (223, 231, 'PERSON')]}), ('In a condition where patients are on so many therapies, to provide one that gives them direct well being feedback is huge it terms of satisfaction and adherence.', {'entities': [(21, 29, 'PERSON'), (45, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (67, 70, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('He believes at some point, empa and entresto will be directly competing with one another for market share.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (27, 31, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (36, 44, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (77, 80, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('That being said the renal benefits remain with empa. He states a trial comparing empa vs an ARB would provide some interesting perspective/insight.', {'entities': [(20, 34, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (47, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (53, 55, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (81, 85, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (92, 95, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States he is thankful we are pursuing data in HF patients w/o diabetes (esp HFpef) to learn more.', {'entities': [(7, 9, 'PERSON'), (22, 24, 'PERSON'), (46, 57, 'PERSON'), (62, 70, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (72, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Goes on to state most pharma companies have not done a complete job in studying patients with GFR45. They are missing a significant patient population.', {'entities': [(22, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (80, 88, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (94, 99, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (101, 105, 'PERSON'), (132, 150, 'PERSON')]}), ('Was pleased to see emperor would capture some of these.', {'entities': [(19, 26, 'PERSON')]}), ('He sees use in patients with compromised renal function as an opportunity due to prescriber hesitation to use ACE/ARB in these patients.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (15, 23, 'PERSON'), (41, 55, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (81, 91, 'PERSON'), (110, 117, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (127, 135, 'PERSON')]}), ('States we are getting to a point were Cardio is willing to initiate therapy but there is still a practical problem with primary care.', {'entities': [(7, 9, 'PERSON'), (38, 44, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (68, 75, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (120, 132, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Larger facilities are able to deal with this better due to system integration and prescriber interaction.', {'entities': [(82, 92, 'PERSON')]}), ('Facility owed physicians is also a positive driver and good targets in these cases. We have to continue to solve the communication/collaboration gab.', {'entities': [(14, 24, 'PERSON'), (84, 86, 'PERSON')]}), ('He sees significant value in the ADR supporting data in emprise and we must continue to commercialize this messaging.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (33, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The positive effects of empa and SGLT2s as a whole is becoming more main stream, even down to primary care level, however, he states "bad news travels best" and is a consistent messaging battle in terms of fighting the amputation narrative among others.', {'entities': [(24, 28, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (33, 39, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (94, 106, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (123, 125, 'PERSON')]}), ('KDM is Dr. Chandrasekhar, Director of Baycare Heart Failure Clinic. As a believer in the SGLT2 class and recognizing empa as the class leader.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 24, 'PERSON'), (26, 34, 'DESIGNATION'), (38, 66, 'ORG'), (73, 81, 'PERSON'), (89, 94, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (117, 121, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (129, 141, 'PERSON')]}), ('Many patients that are identified as candidates but end up not qualifying are often times still put on therapy.', {'entities': [(5, 13, 'PERSON'), (37, 47, 'PERSON'), (103, 110, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Education and familiarity are 2 of the major components of prescribing uptake.', {'entities': [(30, 31, 'CARDINAL'), (59, 70, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM is Leslie Miller, MD. Cardiologist with BayCare Heart Function Clinic.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (6, 20, 'PERSON'), (26, 38, 'DESIGNATION'), (44, 73, 'ORG')]}), ('He things their incremental dosing is a drawback. A number of patients are seen at subtherapeutic doses due to various challenges this presents.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (28, 34, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (62, 70, 'PERSON'), (83, 97, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (98, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Recent trends have pointed to 60/40 in favor of preserved. In tracking since beginning of year, clinic is close to 70% in terms of preserved heart failure.', {'entities': [(30, 35, 'CARDINAL'), (115, 118, 'PERCENT'), (141, 154, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He attributes this to an a population that is living longer, as well as, development of HTN.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (27, 37, 'PERSON'), (88, 91, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('They directly impact measures and tied to patient outcomes. When looking at readmissions, 78% of all their HF readmissions occur within 1st weeks.', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (42, 49, 'PERSON'), (90, 93, 'PERCENT'), (107, 109, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 145, 'DATE')]}), ('While the data is compelling he identifies primary care as one of the key challenge areas in order to gain traction.', {'entities': [(43, 55, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Their primary goal is still not managing co morbid states in combination but rather managing to A1C levels.', {'entities': [(96, 106, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM is Mahesh Amin, CV Medical Director for Baycare Medical Group. They have recently put a care pathway in place for HF-ref, however, where their admission rates are on the rise and admittedly out of control are regarding HF-pef.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (7, 18, 'PERSON'), (23, 39, 'DESIGNATION'), (44, 65, 'ORG'), (67, 71, 'PERSON')]}), ('They are interested in creating a similar pathway but feel their is not enough evidence to put in place.', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (59, 64, 'PERSON')]}), ('Most significant population behind rise of rates are in older women, specifically with T2DM.', {'entities': [(17, 27, 'PERSON'), (56, 67, 'PERSON'), (87, 91, 'PERSON')]}), ('In his opinion, A CAC 1000 is still considered primary, while an MI, etc. would be considered secondary.', {'entities': [(65, 67, 'ORG'), (69, 72, 'ORG')]}), ('The coronary artery calcium score is not a useful diagnostic tool in young middle-aged women with ischemic heart disease', {'entities': [(4, 33, 'ORG'), (87, 92, 'ORG'), (98, 120, 'ORG')]}), ('At this point in the disease process, patients are not calcified which may lead to a misdiagnosis and under-treatment.', {'entities': [(38, 46, 'ORG'), (85, 97, 'ORG'), (102, 117, 'ORG')]}), ('An obstacle for appropriate representation of women in cardiovascular clinical trials is the definition of CAD and HFrEF. The presentation of women with IHD does not fit into the typical obstructive CAD.', {'entities': [(107, 110, 'ORG'), (115, 120, 'ORG')]}), ('IN addition, a majority of patients with non-obstructive IHD develop HFpEF. By adjusting definition of CAD to include this patient population and evaluating for patients with HFpEF, enrollment of women would be improved in ongoing clinical trials.', {'entities': [(27, 35, 'ORG'), (41, 60, 'ORG'), (69, 74, 'ORG'), (103, 106, 'ORG'), (196, 201, 'ORG'), (231, 247, 'ORG')]}), ('She also stated that steroids were generally administered orally or IV for inpatients rather than using ICS devices.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (21, 29, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('There is an ongoing epidemic of CV death in women.', {'entities': [(44, 49, 'ORG')]}), ('This is likely tied to women having a higher incidence of angina and "mini" heart attacks due to difficulty in dilating cardiac microvasculature due to atherosclerosis and coronary microvascular endothelial dysfunction.', {'entities': [(23, 28, 'ORG'), (69, 89, 'ORG'), (152, 167, 'ORG')]}), ('Ischemia in the absence of obstructive CAD is prevalent in 1/3rd of women with ischemic heart disease (IHD) while only 10% in men with IHD.', {'entities': [(119, 122, 'PERCENT')]}), ('This is likely a multifactorial phenomenon tied to a poor representation of women in clinical trials and universal application of male pattern ischemic heart disease identifiers to women.', {'entities': [(76, 81, 'PERSON'), (85, 100, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (130, 134, 'PERSON'), (143, 165, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('This is likely tied to women having a higher incidence of angina and "mini" heart attacks due to difficulty in dilating cardiac microvasculature due to atherosclerosis and coronary microvascular endothelial dysfunction', {'entities': [(23, 28, 'PERSON'), (58, 64, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (69, 89, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (120, 127, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (152, 167, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (181, 218, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Zibrak mentioned that "re-admission due to SPIF could be marker of disease severity and further research is needed where the population that have a higher frequency for re-admissions is randomized in Respimat versus Ellipta or HH treatment arms"', {'entities': [(128, 138, 'PERSON'), (203, 211, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (233, 242, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Met with Joseph Zibrak, MD, Chief Pulmonologist at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) in Boston, MA', {'entities': [(9, 22, 'PERSON'), (28, 47, 'DESIGNATION'), (99, 105, 'GPE')]}), ('The KDM deferred to their PT Chair, Dr. Goldstein, who is both a pulmonologist and a critical care physician as the one within their system who would have an opinion regarding the new COPD exacerbation studies and any potential impact on future treatment practices.', {'entities': [(36, 49, 'PERSON'), (65, 78, 'DESIGNATION'), (99, 108, 'PERSON'), (245, 254, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Nancy Koniecny, R. Ph., MBA, Directory of Pharmacy, Respiratory, and Research Christian Hospital, BCJ - St. Louis MO BJC's Pharmacy leadership Goals for 2018 are focused on the following: 1. Expense Reduction 2. Standardization 3. USP 100 and 4. Diversion.", {'entities': [(59, 77, 'ORG'), (78, 113, 'ORG')]}), ('SCE had agreed to a follow up during a previous discussion to discuss the GOLD update.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON')]}), ('He said that he had not familiarized himself with the changes because he was waiting for me to review them with him.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (13, 15, 'PERSON'), (89, 91, 'PERSON'), (102, 106, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE agrees that initial treatment for all patients should be with bronchodilation and states that his goal is to maximize bronchodilation while utilizing the least amount of medicine possible', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (66, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE states that follow up recommendations appear to be appropriate and are intuitive.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE adds that de-escalation is a big challenge, as most providers tend to add treatment in a non-responsive patient', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (78, 87, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('States that the problem with COPD is two-fold in that the disease itself is under-diagnosed and under-treated, while the patients themselves are often over-treated and not properly diagnosed.', {'entities': [(29, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (121, 129, 'PERSON'), (151, 163, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The center assists CAMC physicians with enrollment, protocol initiation and compliance, and all other regulatory compliance.', {'entities': [(24, 34, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE shared an abstract from a poster that he authored and presented at a conference in Montreal, CA, entitled "Spirometry Utilization in COPD; One Health System\'s Experience".', {'entities': [(137, 141, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (143, 146, 'CARDINAL'), (147, 160, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('This was a retrospective trial of EMR queries to assess the rate of compliance with the ATS/ERS recommendation that the clinical diagnosis of COPD be confirmed by spirometry.', {'entities': [(120, 128, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (142, 146, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('MO KDM was recently given leadership responsibility for research at Christian Hospital (however they are no longer doing oncology reseach at this BJC facility - moved to Barnes and Siteman Cancer Center).', {'entities': [(121, 129, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE agrees that initial treatment for all patients should be with bronchodilation and states that his goal is to maximize bronchodilation while utilizing the least amount of medicine possible.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (24, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (66, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("They found that making the diagnosis of COPD without spirometric confirmation was common and added that even when it was conducted, it was often not performed annually to assess the patient's current severity.", {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (40, 44, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (182, 189, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE hopes to have standards implemented and to conduct follow up research to see improvements from the 13% baseline that they have determined.', {'entities': [(121, 125, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE states that eosinophil levels above 300 or 400 cells/ml are the cut-off level that he determines to be significant for ICS add on.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (65, 67, 'PERSON')]}), ('Upon review of GOLD 2019 SCE offers agreement with the recommendations and states that clinical presentation supersedes levels when in the gray area of 100-200 cells/ml.', {'entities': [(87, 95, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (152, 156, 'CARDINAL'), (160, 165, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM shared that in their COPD management outpatient clinic they use a multidisciplinary approach to help address readmissions.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (19, 24, 'PERSON'), (25, 40, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (52, 58, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (59, 63, 'PERSON')]}), ('Shared that patients are referred to the clinic post an inpatient admission but the rate of attending is about a 1 in 3.', {'entities': [(12, 20, 'PERSON'), (56, 65, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (113, 114, 'CARDINAL'), (118, 119, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('Shared that reasons for this low follow up rate include social determinants of health as well as patients not wanting to come due to "feeling better" and not wanting to see an unknown doctor and care team.', {'entities': [(97, 105, 'PERSON'), (200, 204, 'PERSON')]}), ('Also states that readmissions continue to be an issue for the system but little bedside education is done due to staffing and potential for low likelihood of patient retention.', {'entities': [(158, 165, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE adds that de-escalation is a big challenge, as most providers tend to add treatment in a non-responsive patient.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (78, 87, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (108, 115, 'PERSON')]}), ('KDM states that he is responsible for reading PFTs for the main campus as well as several other hospitals within the system and disagrees with prevalence of sPIF as quoted in the literature.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 18, 'PERSON'), (46, 50, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM shared that he is presenting on behalf of the pulmonology department to a quality committee this afternoon and the focus of the presentation is based on an abstract he presented regarding PFT utilization within the CCF system.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 18, 'PERSON'), (50, 61, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (192, 195, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (219, 222, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("States that when he presented this at a meeting in Montreal a participant equated it to the findings they found at Brigham and Women's on the underutilization of DVT prophylaxis.", {'entities': [(13, 15, 'PERSON'), (101, 105, 'PERSON'), (162, 177, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("KDM was shocked and embarrassed by the low numbers (PFT's performed 13% of the time with COPD diagnosis) and stated most are ordered by pulmonology and not PCP despite free-standing labs in each of the hospitals and family health centers in the community.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (89, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 147, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (156, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('They have not performed an analysis of where the major gaps occur as far as location throughout the system but his goal is to take this information to encourage a system wide educational program on the need for the testing.', {'entities': [(0, 4, 'PERSON'), (111, 114, 'PERSON')]}), ('He shared the dichotomy of COPD being an underdiagnosed disease on one hand but also a condition that is being treated without any confirmation of diagnosis per spirometry.', {'entities': [(27, 31, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (41, 63, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (147, 171, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('This lack of confirmation then leads to the lack of other causes of breathlessness to be investigated.', {'entities': [(68, 82, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Diana Isaacs, PharmD from the Cleveland Clinic presented posted titled "Impact of Physician-Pharmacist Collaboration on A1C in an Interprofessional Endocrinology Clinic"', {'entities': [(30, 46, 'ORG'), (82, 91, 'DESIGNATION'), (92, 102, 'DESIGNATION'), (148, 161, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Benson stated that BIDMC utilizes "The Smith Center for Outcomes Research in Cardiology" for RWE research.', {'entities': [(0, 9, 'PERSON'), (38, 90, 'ORG'), (96, 99, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("In addition, Dr Benson mentioned that the database has nearly 12, 000 patients with T2DM and underlying atherosclerotic CVD that he would be interested in researching and analyzing the utilization and effectiveness of SGLT2i's.", {'entities': [(13, 22, 'PERSON'), (84, 88, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (104, 123, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (218, 226, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('SCE stated that even in an organized health system i.e., the Cleveland Clinic,', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (61, 77, 'ORG')]}), ('The initial meeting with this SCE was regarding questions around PIF.', {'entities': [(30, 33, 'PERSON')]}), ('Met with Dr Mark Benson, Director of Preventative Cardiology at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) in Boston, MA.', {'entities': [(9, 16, 'PERSON'), (112, 118, 'GPE')]}), ('During our last discussion, SCE agreed, after review of the PIF literature and InCheck experience, that he had not considered PIF in terms of the internal resistance of DPIs and the consequences of sPIF for these patients.', {'entities': [(28, 31, 'PERSON'), (79, 97, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (213, 221, 'PERSON')]}), ('Today, the SCE reviewed the recent Ghosh data on prevalence and risk factors associated with suboptimal PIF.', {'entities': [(0, 5, 'PERSON'), (11, 14, 'PERSON'), (35, 40, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE disagrees with the prevalence of sPIF noted within this study (40%) and the prior studies that he has reviewed.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (67, 70, 'PERCENT')]}), ("SCE adds that this would be a consideration for DPI's post-exacerbation.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (48, 53, 'PERSON')]}), ('SCE states that "inhaler selection should not be solely based on peak inspiratory flow".', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (17, 24, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('ppSCE states that they (Cleveland Clinic Pulms) are beginning to pay closer attention to eosinophil levels to determine appropriate ICS treatment.', {'entities': [(0, 5, 'PERSON'), (18, 22, 'PERSON'), (24, 40, 'ORG'), (69, 75, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (89, 106, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (132, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('In addition, he is working with the Quality Improvement (QI) Committee to create a care pipeline, synonymous to an anticoagulation clinic.', {'entities': [(13, 15, 'PERSON'), (115, 137, 'ORG')]}), ('Dr Nan Li is Assistant prof of medicine (pulm) at MSSM, Beth Israel hospital and she noted that even though it is a lot easier to use respimat device in terms of being easy on lungs, but the reality is that we need to use inhalers that are covered for the patients.', {'entities': [(56, 76, 'ORG'), (81, 84, 'PERSON'), (134, 142, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (176, 181, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (207, 209, 'PERSON'), (222, 230, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (256, 264, 'PERSON')]}), ('She also noted that if the patients are trained well on using the inhaler they can get comfortable and it makes it easier.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (27, 35, 'PERSON'), (66, 73, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (74, 78, 'PERSON')]}), ('Dr Gazourian has started a COPD readmission reduction program that involves quantitative imaging to help with differential diagnosis and appropriate coding for COPD, emphysema, lung cancer and IPF.', {'entities': [(0, 12, 'PERSON'), (27, 31, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (193, 196, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The COPD program has correctly diagnosed 65% patients with IPF and increased accurate lung cancer diagnosis.', {'entities': [(59, 62, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 107, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Patients with PAD and CAD have even greater risk.', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (22, 25, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('PAD impairs function and quality of life.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'ORG')]}), ('The COPD program incorporates predictive modeling for Readmission including LOS, Social Determinants of Health to help identify patients high risk for readmissions.', {'entities': [(4, 8, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (76, 79, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (128, 136, 'PERSON')]}), ('There is a new paradigm shift to treat with aspirin and antithrombotic agent to decrease risk in patients with PAD to prevent MI and stroke.', {'entities': [(44, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (97, 105, 'PERSON'), (111, 114, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (126, 128, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The event had over 200 attendees consisting of PCPs, endos and cardiologists.', {'entities': [(4, 9, 'EVENT'), (19, 22, 'CARDINAL'), (47, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (53, 58, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (63, 76, 'PERSON')]}), ('Author stated that they have Pharmacists embedded in PCP offices at CCF and have shown improvements in glucose control in this setting with collaborative practice.', {'entities': [(29, 40, 'PERSON'), (53, 56, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (103, 110, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('She wanted to explore if these results would be replicated in a specialty setting where endos have high degree of knowledge and comfort level titrating and using new meds.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (166, 170, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('She stated that they were still able to show significant improvement in A1c /= 1 even in the specialty setting in patients with T1 and 2 diabetes through physician/pharmacist collaboration. (KA 6/9/2018)', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (16, 20, 'PERSON'), (72, 75, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (114, 122, 'PERSON'), (128, 130, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (137, 145, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Met with John Moorman, PharmD, Endocrine Pharmacotherapy Specialist at the Cleveland Clinic Akron General hospital and faculty at North East Ohio Medical University (NEOMED). KDM rounds with local CCF endocrinologist to see endocrine patients and hospital consults.', {'entities': [(75, 114, 'ORG'), (201, 216, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (234, 242, 'PERSON')]}), ('Most or not continued on oral meds, including SGLT2i due to fluid imbalances, infection, etc.', {'entities': [(25, 34, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (46, 52, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (78, 87, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('For these reasons, most patients started on the class as discharge or in the out-patient space once medically and/or surgically stable.', {'entities': [(24, 32, 'PERSON'), (117, 127, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("KDM is also the coordinator for the Cleveland Clinic's continuous glucose monitor (CGM) program.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (36, 52, 'ORG'), (66, 73, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Also states that there will be a residency project looking at cost saving resource for SGLT-2i and GLP-1 RA.', {'entities': [(99, 107, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("She is a member of the hospital's readmission team that includes COPD admissions and readmissions.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (65, 69, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Key Insights: KDM interested in the prospective pipeline as it applies to treating patients who are high risk metabolic patients.', {'entities': [(14, 17, 'PERSON'), (83, 91, 'PERSON')]}), ('Requested additional guidance in terms of how empagliflozin might be used, in terms of dosing, with respect to HF.', {'entities': [(46, 59, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (87, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (111, 113, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Pharmacist Bonnie LaTourette is Clinical Pharmacist and Preceptor at Community Memorial Hospital in Menomonee Falls, Wisconsin', {'entities': [(18, 28, 'PERSON'), (69, 96, 'ORG'), (117, 126, 'GPE')]}), ('Key Insights: Community Memorial and the Froedtert Medical College of Wisconsin are planning to form a readmission team to address COPD readmissions and admissions.', {'entities': [(131, 135, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('No action has been taken so far other than identifying members of the health care team, including this KDM.', {'entities': [(103, 106, 'ORG')]}), ('During a panel discussion consisted of Richard Nesto, MD (CMO for BILH), Robert Gabbay, MD (CMO for Joslin), Christine McLauglin, MD (Chief of Endo at BILH), Gary Cushing, MD (Endo at BILH) and Mark Benson, MD (Card at BILH).', {'entities': [(58, 61, 'DESIGNATION'), (66, 70, 'ORG'), (100, 106, 'ORG'), (109, 128, 'PERSON'), (134, 139, 'DESIGNATION'), (158, 170, 'PERSON'), (194, 205, 'PERSON')]}), ('Dr Nesto that "SGLT2i should be given to patients with a history of CV risk or events, regardless of other relative risk factors, because the CV benefit data is robust"', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (15, 21, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (41, 49, 'PERSON'), (68, 70, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Nesto stated that "diabetes is a CV disease. T2DM patients should either be on a GLP 1 RA or SGLT2i, key deciding practical patient specific factors are injection vs. PO, insurance, current supportive data and kidney function (eGFR)"', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (22, 30, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (36, 46, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (48, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (165, 180, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (182, 186, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Nesto stated that "the evidence that controlling glycemic control helps to control CV mortality is not that robust and controlling glycemic control does not necessarily change total mortality"', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (89, 98, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Nesto stated that "cardiologists should feel more comfortable using and prescribing SGLT2i\'s because of their CV benefit"', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (22, 35, 'PERSON'), (75, 86, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (87, 95, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (113, 123, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Benson stated that "in a recent look back analysis within Beth Israel\'s EMR database, of the patient\'s that should be on a SGLTi, only 9% were on a SGLTi, out of a total of about 12 to 14K patients that were eligible to be on a SGLT2i"', {'entities': [(0, 9, 'PERSON'), (96, 103, 'PERSON'), (192, 200, 'PERSON'), (231, 237, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('During a panel discussion consisted of Richard Nesto, MD (CMO for BILH), Robert Gabbay, MD (CMO for Joslin), Christine McLauglin, MD (Chief of Endo at BILH), Gary Cushing, MD (Endo at BILH) and Mark Benson, MD (Card at BILH)', {'entities': [(58, 61, 'DESIGNATION'), (66, 70, 'ORG'), (100, 106, 'ORG'), (109, 128, 'PERSON'), (158, 170, 'PERSON'), (194, 205, 'PERSON')]}), ('Dr Nesto stated that "it is very difficult to have T2DM patients meeting all guideline driven criteria, e.g., LDL, BP, weight loss, nutrition, etc., it is relatively difficult to get T2DM patients down to a RR of 1"', {'entities': [(0, 8, 'PERSON'), (51, 55, 'PERSON'), (56, 64, 'PERSON'), (110, 113, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (207, 209, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Dr Ramanathan, Endo SCE affiliated with BJC Medical Group of Missouri explained, DECLARE definitively confirms the CV benefit of SGLT2's as the 3rd body of evidence.", {'entities': [(0, 13, 'PERSON'), (20, 23, 'PERSON'), (40, 57, 'ORG'), (115, 117, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (129, 136, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('However, the trial was unsuccessful in demonstrating CV mortality benefit as seen in ERO.', {'entities': [(56, 65, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (85, 88, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Due to Dapa's lack of mortality benefit, and Cana's label warning for LLA, Empa has become the agent of choice within the class.", {'entities': [(22, 31, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (70, 73, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (75, 79, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He confided that Revefenacin has made significant inroad at their institutions due to the belief among clinicians that it provides superior improvement in FEV1 among severe and very severe COPD patients, especially given that its nebulized mode of delivery is better for severe patients who may experience inhaler coordination issues.', {'entities': [(103, 113, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (189, 193, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (194, 202, 'PERSON'), (306, 313, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM shared that although the 38% RRR in CV death with empa is significant and most of his patients are co-morbid, he is a self-proclaimed "slow adopter" and needs to process information and wait for hear experience from others before he is comfortable initiating a new medication.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (54, 58, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (86, 89, 'PERSON'), (90, 98, 'PERSON'), (269, 279, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Stated he attended a promotional program which was helpful to hear from another cardiologist and appreciates his PCP colleagues that have high utilization and experience.', {'entities': [(7, 9, 'PERSON'), (80, 92, 'DESIGNATION'), (109, 112, 'PERSON'), (113, 116, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Stated that this is not unique to empa and cited many other entrants to the market where he follows the same process, most recently Entresto which he just started using despite being available for several years.', {'entities': [(34, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (132, 140, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Vishal Gupta MD interventional cardiologist Borgess Health stated at his organization hospitalist do the majority of the discharges.', {'entities': [(0, 15, 'PERSON'), (34, 46, 'DESIGNATION'), (47, 61, 'ORG'), (72, 75, 'PERSON'), (89, 100, 'DESIGNATION')]}), ('Empagliflozin is not on the inpatient formulary and thus available to use the EMR for discharge planning or instructions.', {'entities': [(0, 13, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (28, 37, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (78, 81, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Vishal Gupta MD, interventional cardiologist at Borgess Health stated that empagliflozin is not available on the inpatient formulary and thus is not available to be added to a discharge order set that he wants to develop.', {'entities': [(0, 18, 'PERSON'), (35, 47, 'DESIGNATION'), (51, 65, 'ORG'), (78, 91, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (116, 125, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("We must optimize benefit and decrease risk. The emphasis can't be just on bleeding.", {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON')]}), ('Bleeds are bad but so are strokes.', {'entities': [(0, 6, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (26, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("We need to address when doctors don't want to take the risk, anticoagulants are not used or under dose NOACs.", {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (24, 31, 'PERSON'), (61, 75, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (98, 102, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (103, 108, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Government agencies emphasize bleeds too much and all bleeds are not preventable.', {'entities': [(0, 19, 'ORG'), (30, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('We need to manage patients based on evidence based practice and need to do adequate risk assessment for both risk and safety.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (18, 26, 'PERSON'), (51, 59, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr Aristea Gugger, MD at Bridgeport Hospital, presented poster #176 titled "A Not So Sweet DKA: A Case of Euglycemic Diabetic Ketoacidosis Caused by Dapagliflozin/Liraglutide Combination".', {'entities': [(0, 17, 'PERSON'), (25, 44, 'ORG'), (106, 138, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (149, 162, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (163, 174, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("Author stated it was not Farxiga that caused DKA, it was the addition of Liraglutide to patient's treatment. Author proceeded to say that treating physicians need to assess relative insulin sensitivity, depletion of glycogen, dehydration, nausea and vomiting as all contributing factors to developing DKA.", {'entities': [(45, 48, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (73, 84, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (88, 95, 'PERSON'), (98, 107, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (141, 149, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (216, 224, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (226, 237, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('(NS, 3/23/2019) Abstract found below: https://www.abstractsonline.com/pp8/#!/5752/presentation/8490', {'entities': [(5, 14, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (77, 81, 'CARDINAL'), (95, 99, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('Dr Ajinkya Pawar, Research Specialist at Brigham & Women\'s Hospital Department of Medicine presented poster titled "Health Care Costs and Medication Burden in Routine Care Inhibitors of Empagliflozin: A first analysis from the emapgliflozin comparative effectiveness and safety (EMPRISE) study.', {'entities': [(138, 148, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (172, 182, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (186, 199, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (227, 252, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('He reports with a mean follow-up of 5.4 months, the first analysis of EMPRISE demonstrated similar medication burden and total cost in patients with EMPA vs DPP4i.', {'entities': [(0, 2, 'PERSON'), (36, 39, 'CARDINAL'), (52, 57, 'CARDINAL'), (99, 109, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (135, 143, 'PERSON'), (149, 153, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (157, 162, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('The higher pharmacy cost in the empa group vs DPP4i group was offset by a trend towards lower medical cost and further studies are needed in patients with T1DM to factor in risk of DKA. (NS, 6/9/2019)', {'entities': [(32, 36, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (46, 57, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (141, 149, 'PERSON'), (155, 159, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (181, 184, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (191, 199, 'DATE')]}), ("Dr. McDonnell, Director of the Diabetes Management Program at Brigham and Women's Hospital, stated that based on the D2d study she will continue Vit D supplementation in her patients with prediabetes since the study showed the safety of high dose Vit D.", {'entities': [(0, 13, 'PERSON'), (15, 23, 'DESIGNATION'), (31, 58, 'ORG'), (117, 126, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (127, 130, 'PERSON'), (170, 173, 'PERSON'), (174, 182, 'PERSON'), (188, 205, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (242, 246, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('She commented she would use high dose Vit D as a supplement for patients with vit D deficiency but would not use Vit D supplementation for all patients with prediabetes realizing that the D2d study showed no significant reduction in the occurrence of T2DM in patients with prediabetes.', {'entities': [(14, 17, 'PERSON'), (64, 72, 'PERSON'), (157, 168, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (188, 197, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (251, 255, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('She stated that this analysis included mostly patients taking canagliflozin (77%).', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (46, 54, 'PERSON'), (62, 75, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (77, 80, 'PERCENT')]}), ('She hypothesized on a hemodynamic effect that may have potential harm in patients without CVD.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (73, 81, 'PERSON'), (90, 93, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ("She commented that she believes that there are differences between agents within the SGLT2i class and she has not seen data associating empagliflozin with any lack of benefit in patients without CVD compared to GLP1RA's.", {'entities': [(19, 22, 'PERSON'), (85, 91, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (136, 149, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (178, 186, 'PERSON'), (211, 217, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('I commented on our data associating a benefit of empagliflozin in CV outcomes across the CV risk continuum. (SM, 6/9/2019)', {'entities': [(49, 62, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (66, 77, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (113, 121, 'DATE')]}), ("KDM states that it will be helpful to provide educational insight on BI's portfolio of respiratory products once the meeting occurs.", {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (87, 98, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Key Insights: KDM had unsolicited request for use of SGLT2s and empagliflozin in patients with T1D.', {'entities': [(14, 17, 'PERSON'), (53, 59, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (64, 77, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (81, 89, 'PERSON')]}), ('Would like to see they studies and data that show outcomes for T1D patients: R: Will provide EASE trial and other related Veeva publications in support of T1D treatment with Empagliflozin.', {'entities': [(18, 22, 'PERSON'), (63, 66, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (67, 75, 'PERSON'), (122, 127, 'ORG'), (155, 168, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (174, 187, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Key Insights: KDM had a favorable view of the Emprise data as a RWE study.', {'entities': [(14, 17, 'PERSON'), (46, 53, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (64, 67, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Stated that is was complementary of her understanding of ERO with additional outcomes related to HHF.', {'entities': [(36, 39, 'PERSON'), (57, 60, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('KDM has not seen currently the use of empagliflozin in the institutional setting as a complement to other HF therapies.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (38, 51, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (106, 118, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Dr. Elizabeth Buckley, Pharm. D., CDE, Associate Professor, Concordia University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin presented at the 2019 Madison Clinical Conference (Diabetes Focus), April 10-11, 2019 in Madison, Wisconsin.', {'entities': [(0, 13, 'PERSON'), (19, 28, 'DESIGNATION'), (30, 50, 'ORG'), (52, 61, 'GPE'), (63, 72, 'GPE'), (90, 122, 'EVENT'), (124, 132, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (147, 150, 'CARDINAL'), (154, 162, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Presentation was "Newer Diabetes Therapies Part 1: Non-Insulin Therapies.', {'entities': [(51, 62, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('Believes data CV forthcoming for dapagliflozin will be equal to that of empagliflozin and canagliflozin in terms of RRR for CV death (misperception) 3. KDM stated (misperception) that Ozempic had a 25% RRR in CV death not 3P MACE albeit it does not have a label approved for this indication.', {'entities': [(33, 46, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (72, 85, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (90, 103, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (116, 119, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (149, 150, 'CARDINAL')]}), ('Key Insights: T2D1. KDM believes the MOA related to SGLT2s is mainly limited to glucosuria and did not mention any other possible MOA(s) or benefits.', {'entities': [(0, 3, 'PERSON'), (17, 20, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (32, 38, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (110, 115, 'MEDICAL_TERM')]}), ('GLP1s are the most robust diabetes treatment because they address most of the issue in the egregious eleven.', {'entities': [(0, 5, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (26, 44, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (53, 57, 'PERSON')]}), ("Number one issue of any treatment selection for T2D is COST! Even before efficacy and safety -- If they cannot afford the medication, it's not a choice!3.5.", {'entities': [(24, 33, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (48, 54, 'MEDICAL_TERM'), (59, 60, '